Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Previously on
Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
This is Dr. Korby.
At first she was a fellow.
but she quickly became more.
She was running the excavation
site on Vadia Nine with me.
Vulcans have an ancient technique
of regulating pain
through meditation.
When we joined minds.
I absorbed your pain.
I saw something.
- It felt both a part of you and not.
- Was it Gorn?
This openness to new
life experiences suits you.
Okay. Who's this?
My little brother.
Starfleet's Public Relations.
They may commission
a feature-length documentary
of Starfleet.
Junior medical officer's log.
stardate 2184.4.
Reporting from the USS Enterprise.
Enterprise.
I will never get tired
of saying that.
The last six months stationed
here have been awesome.
Today started out
like any other day here.
me working in sickbay.
But after today
I know my life is never gonna be
the same again.
Oh. Exciting. isn't it?
Yeah. if you're into
that sort of thing.
Nurse Chapel and Dr. Korby
are about to make history.
Well. this could change
the way we view mortality.
And Korby's work
on molecular memory
and corporeal transference.
The idea
that ancient man's fascination
with resurrection
and reincarnation
could all be based on
forgotten technology? I mean...
If you're into
that sort of thing.
I may have read
some of his papers.
Should I expect
a transfer request
- from you to archaeological medicine?
- Never.
I mean. as fun as it sounds
to dig up old worlds
and find lost medical science.
- I like where I'm at.
- Well.
you can make your own mark
on history
by charging the dermal wands
at all the biobed stations
before Captain Batel gets here
for her treatment.
Gotcha. sir. On it.
You're sure
the Enterprise's deflector array
won't overpower
the magnetic anomaly?
How many times
do I have to promise you
- it's all gonna be fine?
- I know. I know.
You. uh. you let Pike know
how-how sacred this place was
- to the people here. right?
- Do you really think
that Starfleet
is just gonna waltz on in there.
phasers blasting.
and obliterate a heritage site?
Uh. no.
But-but-but can you blame me?
I mean...
sometimes people that-that are
used to giving orders struggle
- when-when receiving them. huh?
- God. you're so right.
I'm just gonna go
and hypospray Captain Pike
so he doesn't give us.
like. any trouble at all.
How much Tarazine is sublethal?
Just always get
the numbers all mixed-up.
You having fun?
Maybe just a blow to the head?
Command function's left lobe. right?
Mm-hmm. mm-hmm.
Okay. look. maybe I'm being
a little paranoid.
Oh. you. my dear?
Never.
Okay.
I know how much work
you've. you've put in.
lobbying Captain Pike to help.
There's just no getting below
the planet's surface
without a starship.
And I am more than grateful.
- It's just that I always get nervous...
- You always get nervous
- before a dig.
- ...before a dig.
I know.
I'll see you soon. Roger.
Yes. you will.
Hurry down.
Don't make me wait.
Chapel.
Uh. quick question.
How's Spock doing?
Fine?
I haven't seen him today.
Has he. uh. said anything
about Roger being here?
Um...
I mean. I know
you guys have been...
spending more time.
getting closer
- these last months.
- Oh. No.
No. please don't be
one of those women.
This is why I don't do this.
Oh. me? No. Oh.
Heck no.
I'm good.
Spock and I made it very clear
with each other.
No labels.
no complicated expectations.
Just fun times.
Please don't make it weird.
Uh. y-you're good with that?
Look. if you're really worried
about Spock behaving
around Korby. then just ask him.
- We're all adults here. right?
- Mm.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's amazing.
With Spock's brain.
M'Benga's research.
and Chapel's genetic expertise.
frankly. it's a...
- Don't say "miracle."
- Okay.
Top-notch science.
How's my favorite patient doing?
Great. actually.
Thank you. Joseph.
What you've done here.
I owe it to all of you.
How are the dermal wands
looking?
All accounted for. sir.
Every biobed station
fully charged.
And the remote synthesizers?
I thought you would ask.
so I recharged them. too.
Good. So you won't be late.
Uh. late for what?
The mission brief.
The landing party's
meeting soon.
The landing party?
On Vadia Nine?
You've requested
away team assignment six times.
You've earned it.
Just don't embarrass me
with Dr. Korby.
I'm sorry. I'm just so excited.
Go.
They'll start without you.
Mm!
Whoo!
My first
official research mission
on an alien planet.
I've been dreaming of this
since I was first accepted
to Starfleet Academy.
And now it's my time to shine.
Lieutenant Spock.
Why are we always
so quiet when we need to talk?
Is there something to discuss?
I am...
glad to see you
and Lieutenant Noonien-Singh
spending more time together.
She is an excellent
dance instructor.
That. too.
Um...
Roger's... feeling nervous
about the dig.
And. um...
you know. I know you guys
are. like. friends now...
A relative term.
I just want to be s-sure that
things are gonna go smoothly
- down there.
- You do not trust me.
Not to worry. Christine.
I have instituted
certain safeguards
to ensure
it will all go smoothly.
What do you.
what do you mean. "safeguards"?
Ah. great! Crewmates!
I don't have to go
into the briefing alone.
I interrupted something.
didn't I?
The M'Kroon have declined
Federation membership
on multiple occasions. which
is why they're only allowing
a small landing party.
All right. Chapel.
you'll be boots on the ground.
Give us the go-ahead once the
signal amplifiers are in place.
Has the science team
finished adjusting
- the deflector arrays?
- Yes.
And I will be monitoring
the adjustments in real time.
here aboard the Enterprise.
Monitoring from the ship
as a safeguard.
You're not coming down
to the planet.
Chapel. this is
your mission. Any last...
thoughts or words?
Could you do that again?
Mr. Ortegas.
Sorry. I just needed to adjust
for subspace static.
- It interferes with my...
- Mr. Ortegas.
Erica promised
you wouldn't be a problem.
You'll get better footage
if you just keep it quiet.
Sorry.
Young man.
if there is anything you want
to see in Engineering.
anything at all.
I am more than comfortable
around a camera.
You know what. Pelia.
let's not encourage...
Ensign Gamble.
would you kindly read the first
paragraph of our mission brief?
"To commemorate
the Federation's centennial.
"documentarian Humberto Ortegas
"has been given
security clearance
to record Enterprise's
current roster of missions."
Okay. according to that.
we're stuck with each other.
But maybe just try
to keep the cameras
out of the way.
Let's go dig up the past.
N'Jal.
Thank you for allowing us
to document this...
historic occasion.
It is such an honor to meet you.
I hear the M'Kroon have
a unique vocal range.
Come.
Let me show you.
Hi.
How are you?
Good.
Our magnetic anomaly?
You were right about this place.
There is indeed some form
of advanced technology
hiding beneath us.
Let's set up.
see what it is.
Okay.
They keep you busy. huh?
Uh...
We don't all get to play
with toys.
Come here.
Let me show you something.
So. it's intuitive.
A.I. lenses track movement
and inflections in speech
that indicate strong emotions.
Uh. it clocks nonverbal cues?
It's always looking
for the subtext. the heat.
Could be why it's focused
on us right now.
Done here. Uhura.
How's it going over there?
Finished.
Chapel to the bridge.
The pylons are set.
- Ready when you are.
- Copy.
Stand by for deflector beams.
Captain. we're gonna need
a bigger landing party.
Space.
The final frontier.
These are the voyages
of the starship Enterprise.
Its five-year mission:
to explore strange new worlds...
...to seek out new life
and new civilizations...
...to boldly go
where no one has gone before.
I knew you'd have to come down
and see this all for yourself.
What'd I tell you?
You owe me a drink.
The M'Kroons vetoed our request
to send more personnel.
so Spock and I are
the only ones coming.
Copy that.
Uh. we found an access panel
with symbols
in an unknown language.
These symbols are the interface?
Maybe. Or instructions.
Or a warning.
They have a remarkable
similarity
to the M'Kroonian alphabet.
So. five years ago.
hundreds of light-years
from here.
I discovered this.
I believe it is
a royal insignia.
So this place could be
some sort of temple or palace.
All I know is.
I found this ring on Polaris 12.
But there are similar
symbol sets on Praetorian.
Where we found tablets...
That Christine matched
with ancient texts here
on Vadia Nine.
We think the M'Kroon are
the direct descendants
of an advanced civilization
that could travel across
multiple galaxies.
- Ancient astronauts?
- We don't know.
but they claim to have achieved
immortality.
A common myth.
A fantasy many cultures share.
But in this case
our research suggests
that their secret
to immortality...
Had something to do with
creating quantum instability
at a molecular level.
Fascinating.
- Right?
- Okay.
so I cross-referenced
the symbols
with Praetorian
and ancient M'Kroonian.
"The path to absolution.
only with blood given freely."
Blood given freely?
A ritual sacrifice.
An offering to the gods.
Blood magic.
On M'Kroon. our ancestors
would sacrifice
to stand before
the deities of time.
Whoa. hold on.
Just take a moment
before we choose
the dramatic option.
Don't.
Really?
It worked.
Nothing foreign detected
in your bloodstream.
Any pain. symptoms of any kind?
I'll live. Ensign.
Well. Chapel.
this is your party.
I'm guessing you want
to come with me on point.
Watch your footing and
try not to touch anything.
Sadly. that would defeat my
entire purpose here. Lieutenant.
Well. you know what I mean.
Comms on the ship are down.
Which means we'd have to
go outside to report back.
More importantly...
We cannot transport
from inside this chamber.
- Far from ideal.
- It's open here.
Huh.
Some kind of light barrier.
Yeah. whatever it is.
I don't like it.
Scared of El Cucuy?
I'm not five.
and it's not my bedtime.
Hey. what's that.
an oversized...?
Bag. I was gonna say bag.
but. nope. it's a body.
Well. they're not immortal.
The readings indicate
these remains are centuries old.
Cause of death appears to be
starvation.
They were trapped down here.
Just a hunch. but it looks to me
like they were trying
to rob the place.
This discovery raises
the threat level of the mission.
We must exit.
report this to the captain.
and reassess our investigation.
Hold on a second.
Isn't Christine in charge
of this mission?
Actually. Spock is the senior
science officer.
Well. I don't answer
to Starfleet. now. do I?
Look... this is not the first time
that a landing party mission
has faced
escalated but not lethal danger.
Starfleet protocol
clearly states
a landing party
must alert the ship
to any clear and present danger.
- But nothing dangerous has happened.
- Spock.
wh-what we can discover here
is important.
Not just to me.
not just to Roger.
Not even just to science.
N'Jal. the M'Kroons.
this is their history.
As you've stated.
this is not just about us.
N'Jal. we are your guests here.
Would you prefer if we cease
or proceed?
Tika-mak chan tario pik-tah.
Vika. chan tario tah.
Eek lok to. ma vika tario.
Closest translation:
"My people have a deep desire.
We wish to know
the core of our being."
Trust is a two-way street.
Spock.
We will continue
with the mission.
I got you.
Roger.
It's a memory stone.
- It's just like the ones
we found on Praetorian. - Mm-hmm.
Christine. this...
this is exactly
what we came here to find.
Careful.
Gamble!
Gamble. Gamble. Gamble. Gamble.
you okay?
Easy. easy. I've got you.
We just sent the fragments
to Pelia for analysis.
The orb triggered
when he picked it up.
Gather the rest of the team
and beam back aboard
immediately.
Understood. Captain.
How's Gamble?
He's stable.
M'Benga's already working on
bioengineering him new eyes.
We found something.
I think this is
some kind of register.
- There are thousands of names here.
- Some of which
are actually on the artifact
you found among the dead.
Guys. this is great. and there's
so much to learn here.
but it's time to go.
- We got to get back to the ship.
- Um...
N'Jal and I are.
are gonna stay behind.
Waited my whole life
for a find like this.
Roger.
Hey.
- Look at this.
- What is it?
I sent a camera
through the doorway.
Before or after
we said to pull out?
- That's the next chamber?
- Mm-hmm.
Mika-tah. Vezda-pah.
Um...
- What's he saying?
- "Danger."
Mika-tah. Vezda-pah.
Not "danger."
- "Evil."
- N'Jal. what's wrong?
We're all gonna die.
N'Jal. N'Jal!
The door.
Hello? Who's here?
Why is it dark?
Try not to sit up.
- Is this why I can't see?
- No.
Your bulbus oculi were ejected
from their orbital sockets.
- I lost my eyes?
- This should be regenerating them.
But right now it's just keeping
them from deteriorating further.
When was I injured?
You were injured on the planet
by a grenade of some type.
We're still analyzing
the fragments.
- The landing party? Are they okay?
- The others are fine.
They should be back here
any minute.
My short-term memory
was damaged.
Hopefully. it's not permanent.
A post-traumatic
stress response.
- Status?
- Conscious. Alert.
And scared
but happy to be alive.
Well. that's understandable.
Rest. I'll be right back.
All right. what's the full report?
I've shifted my initial assessment
from flash burn
to some kind of agent.
- Biological weapon?
- Maybe.
And before you ask.
he's not contagious.
But something is preventing
his eyes from regenerating.
Okay. how are you holding up?
I'm fine.
You know. when Gamble
came on to replace Chapel.
it was supposed to be temporary.
but she came back.
And he stayed.
It's no secret
I'm fond of the boy.
He wasn't ready
for away missions.
Joseph. you know more than most.
we can't protect everyone.
But if anyone's going to
help him. it's going to be you.
It's locked. Why now?
The structure must have engaged
a safety protocol.
Christine. it didn't trigger
when you and La'An
took Gamble through.
Or when you came back.
When you unlocked the door.
it took a sample of your DNA.
You were scanned.
And we all entered together
as a group.
Your biosignature kept us safe.
So. N'Jal tried to leave
without me.
Well. if the door liked me then.
it's done liking me now.
No. no. there has
to be another way out.
We know what happens
if we try to wait things out.
You are suggesting we go deeper
into the structure?
We stay here and we starve.
Either way is a risk.
I prefer the one
that keeps us active.
May I?
Yeah.
La'An.
Beto's camera's still showing
the feed from the other chamber.
It looks safe. relatively.
So that chamber is on
the other side of this door?
Yes.
Okay. let's try it.
Chapel?
Maybe this door still likes you.
Okay.
That worked.
As a precaution. we should use
the same formation as before.
Yeah.
Precaution against being
incinerated by burning light?
Chapel with me. Uhura. Beto.
Spock and Korby.
you take up the rear.
Look at it.
Roger. this...
They're gone.
Wait. Let's think about this.
- We could get separated. too.
- Yeah.
Huh. what about comms?
- I know we can't reach the ship. but...
- Maybe.
maybe the interference is
coming from the building itself.
La'An to Spock. do you read me?
Spock here. I read you.
Dr. Korby and I appear to be
in a room by ourselves.
We copy. too. It's Beto and I.
Also alone.
Together but alone.
We have comms.
I'd call that a silver lining.
Okay.
Stay put wherever you are.
No arguments here.
Agreed.
Do you guys have a giant statue
in the middle of your chamber?
Our room looks just like
the one we left.
Dead grave robbers and all.
Perhaps we should surveil
our respective areas
- and report back.
- All right.
Let's reconvene on comms
in ten minutes.
And stay alert.
Inconclusive.
That tickles.
You're awake.
This isn't doing anything.
is it?
No. it's not.
What's happening to me. Joseph?
Hmm.
You used my first name.
I'm sorry. Dr. M'Benga.
- You're right. I...
- No. it's good.
It's more than time
you feel comfortable around me.
I guess a close call like that
can really put some things
in perspective.
This reading...
Hold on.
All right. let's try this again.
What?
What is it? What does it say?
- We need more tests.
- Doctor...
Joseph. just tell me.
There's no other way
to put this.
your brain is dead.
The scan shows entire lobes.
electrons. neurons.
- all shut down.
- No.
That's impossible.
How am I alive?
- I-I'm awake. we're talking.
- Yes. I know. Exactly like I said.
- We need more tests.
- I'm not dead!
- Hey. take a breath. I didn't say that.
- No. but. but.
but...
I'm giving you a sedative.
Relax.
But...
Stay calm.
I'll figure this out.
- Chapel.
- Hmm?
Why is there an Earth language
at your ancient dig site?
It's Chinese.
"Here stands the Beholder.
sentry of eternal bridges."
A biosignature?
This thing has
a life sign reading.
Doesn't act very alive.
Oh. well. technically.
it's both alive and not.
Also. it's not really here.
Hmm. well.
I'm looking right at it. so...
On a quantum level.
the-the particles that make up
this Beholder
are in constant flux.
Both here and not here.
Quantum instability
at a molecular level.
Great.
So what does that mean?
Not a clue.
Brilliant.
Is this really the same room
we were just in?
Perhaps. but look.
I wouldn't go that way
after what happened to N'Jal.
Do you really think
it's a fantasy?
You balk at the idea
of immortality?
You don't think
that the science exists
to prevent our consciousness
from fading?
I do not balk at your ideas.
Dr. Korby.
I merely believe you neglect
to take the proper precautions.
Huh?
I said you neglect
to take the proper...
No. no. no. no. look here.
Above the names.
this-this word. it means. um.
parasites or hitchhikers.
And-and this word.
it means well or pit.
This word... Vezda.
Vezda.
The M'Kroon word for evil?
Yes.
Only here it's used.
Vezda. it-it...
it isn't singular.
Fascinating.
What is it?
What do you see?
Thousands of them.
Our landing party
never came back.
My brother didn't
sign up for this.
All of the M'Kroon liaisons
on the project have
suddenly gone radio silent.
The locals have cut us off.
So send down
another landing party.
Aye. They cannot keep us
from getting our people back.
Unfortunately. they can.
We're here with a special
access agreement.
I can reach out.
if the ambassador is no help.
we will go down there.
What do we know
about the explosive device
that we encountered?
Technically it's a...
It's a. it's a containment unit.
On its own. the orb
should not have exploded.
It's possible it got separated
from its power source
and weakened.
But best we can figure is
that the energy source
inside of it forced its way out.
Forced its way out. how?
Could it have been sentient?
Oh. we don't know.
Pelia. what aren't you
telling us?
This thing...
is older than anything
I've ever seen.
What do you think was
inside of it?
I'm not sure.
And I have no scientific way
of putting this.
but whatever it is.
it gives me the heebie-jeebies.
Ensign Gamble.
Captain to Security.
Meet me in sickbay.
Rukiya. what a beautiful name.
It's a shame
you had to let her go.
I never told you about Rukiya.
Hmm. you're right.
My mistake.
Do you think that woman
who came to you
was really your daughter?
Or do you think it was
something wearing her skin?
Something that drank her tears
and fed off her screams?
Who am I talking to right now?
What the hell?
What was that?
A foreign intelligence.
Inside me?
How was it talking?
It had my voice.
I don't know yet.
Why would it say those things?
- Relax. Take a breath.
- Joseph...
I'm having a reaction.
feels like a migraine.
You.
Cali-katchna!
Mika-tah. Vezda-pah!
Captain...
Marie!
Marie.
Marie. it's me...
I don't want to have to do this.
- everybody just leave me alone.
- Easy. easy.
- Gamble. it's me.
- Dr. M'Benga?
I didn't mean to do that.
I believe you.
Please. put the phaser down.
Why is everybody
trying to hurt me?
They are not.
we're trying to help you.
Stand down.
Give him room.
If I let them take me.
will you fix me?
I just want to be me again.
I've got you. don't worry.
Sickbay or the brig. sir?
Scans are showing
this pillar is shifting
in and out of this reality.
You mean the freaky underground
hell hole gets even freakier?
We're just going to die here
like those explorers we found.
Hey.
Look at me.
I've been where you are
right now.
and I know
that all you can focus on
is how bad this all feels.
All I can think about is being
trapped down here alone with...
We're not alone.
We are going to find
our way out of this.
Together.
Just breathe.
Thank you.
I'm seeing the impossible.
Look.
Uhura to landing party.
I think I've got something.
We have some
interesting finds. too.
Indeed. there is much
to discuss.
The statue in here is giving off
unstable phase variances.
And it has a life sign.
Korby and I discovered
the presence of sentient life.
Curious. I do not recall
this injury.
Look. all of that is amazing.
This whole place is.
but the thing is
we are all still together.
How is that even possible?
The intuitive software.
it's-it's picking up our
biosignatures and placing us
- all in the same room.
- This is layered dimensional space.
We're not in different rooms.
This is different planes
of existence.
We never left the first chamber.
If subatomic instability
was being
utilized as a means
to immortality. then...
Then maybe this place is a lab
or a-a fountain of youth?
I fear it is not that simple.
Spock found life-forms
trapped inside orbs.
just like the one
that injured Gamble.
The tablet called them
parasites. Hitchhikers.
Unwelcome guests.
It is possible phase-shifting
through dimensions
to achieve immortality
had a side effect.
Of bringing something through.
What kind of something?
Somethings...
from somewhere else.
What if this place isn't
a palace or a lab?
What if it's a prison?
I'm sorry. but we'll have
to look after you from here.
It's okay.
I understand.
What's gonna happen to me?
I wish I could say.
This inscription reads
"Here and not here."
On Praetorian.
artifacts were sometimes set
into pedestals like this.
Component parts.
Together they might be the key
to unifying
the dimensional shift.
The relief there.
- The signet ring.
- I still have it.
Okay. but how do we get those
two things to work together
whilst stuck on different
dimensional planes?
Put the tablet
where it says tabernacle.
Done.
Uhura. the ring.
Okay. What now?
I'm the key
to all of this. right?
Christine.
Curiouser and curiouser.
Okay. so we're
all back together. but...
...how do we get to the door?
How are you?
In case I go
off the rails again?
Mm.
M'Benga didn't want
to release you to the quarters
without knowing
it was safe. and...
I knew I wouldn't need it.
Chris. I don't know
what happened in there.
Something inside of me
just snapped.
How's Gamble?
In custody.
He's not quite himself. either.
I remember seeing him. but it...
It wasn't him.
He was something else.
And I felt...
...like something else.
What?
I can't describe it.
I just had this
overwhelming desire to kill...
...no. to exterminate him.
Well. you're back now.
Has anyone else
reacted to him this way?
No. We have to consider
that it's an expression
of the Gorn DNA in your body.
We don't know all the downsides.
This feeling I had.
I can't explain it.
but it felt... old.
Okay.
Whatever it is.
we'll figure it out.
- The landing party?
- Still missing.
Captain. I've got the M'Kroon
Ambassador on standby for you.
Patch it through.
Okay.
So. we got to find a way
to get to the door.
Of course.
In this reconstituted
dimensional space.
inverted causality coexists.
Uh. yeah. you're gonna have
to walk me through that one.
Inverted causality
is a dimension
where effects can happen
before cause.
It's. uh... It's paradoxical.
Yes. and theoretical. but also
scientifically possible.
When Dr. Korby and I
were separated.
there was a bridge here.
And that panel by the door
was glowing white.
Well. it's red now.
Yes. So we must have
turned it on.
Effect before cause?
So you're saying... No. no.
No.
- What? "No. no" what?
- Yes.
We must walk across
this empty space
and turn on the bridge.
Guard. Guard!
Your mother. She's in pain.
Something's hurting her.
What?
Her name... it's Jara.
She wants to tell you
what's hurting her.
Who told you that?
You did. You let me die alone.
Nope. I-I'm not doing that.
No way.
Our other option
is to remain here and starve.
A sound tactical argument.
So... you lead. I'll follow.
Just don't step on my toes.
I am also willing
to take this risk.
However. I believe
that we must. in fact.
commit to doing this
all together.
And Nurse Chapel is the key.
Don't do it. Christine.
Theoretical doesn't mean
you can just go and walk on air.
Nurse Chapel.
I may no longer have
your confidence on many things.
but this is a matter of science.
And what hangs in the balance
is our survival.
We are on a two-way street.
And now I'm asking you
to simply trust me.
Roger. it's time to go.
No.
Christine. listen to reason.
Yes. it is a risk
walking out there.
but in the short time
that I've known you.
you've never been afraid
of taking a chance.
Remember what you said to me.
all those months ago?
"Nothing in life is guaranteed."
That's what makes life
worth living.
Okay.
Roger. leave the relic
where it is.
It's the only thing
keeping us together.
Okay.
So this is where you saw it?
Yes.
Okay.
Well...
let's go.
Let's get out of here.
Hey. We're alive.
Take the win.
Senior officer command codes.
please.
or I will kill you.
What? What are you saying?
I have the boy's thoughts.
his memories.
You can take control
of this vessel from Engineering.
Lanthanite child.
- Wha...
- Perhaps I take him instead?
Hmm?
Or him?
Hurt them and you die next.
Oh...
you couldn't kill your favorite
ensign now. could you?
Help. please.
Dr. M'Benga. it's me.
it's really me.
Don't hurt me.
Fight it. You can fight it.
No. Joseph. I don't think
he's really in there.
He is.
Let the boy go. Please.
Take me.
No!
W-Where did you send it?
Nowhere.
Thanks to Pelia and Lieutenant
Scott's quick thinking.
we should not be seeing
the Vezda again.
Are you sure it'll hold?
Until we learn more
about this entity.
the transport buffer
is the best proxy we have
for a layered
dimensional prison.
What about the rest of them?
Starfleet and the M'Kroon
are already working together
to establish a security
perimeter around the site.
Apparently.
they're starting to see
the benefits of the Federation.
You know. if Ensign Gamble.
or...
rather. the entity
inside of him.
had taken hold
of the ship's phaser banks...
He could have set them all free.
An army of cosmic beings like
that set loose on the galaxy?
I'm sorry. Doctor. I know
you were fond of the boy.
but he was gone.
Were they evil. Captain?
I saw the recordings
of what Gamble did.
and the things he said.
Good and evil
are relative terms. son.
Nonsense. There is evil
in this universe.
as sure as there is good.
A-As sure as there is matter.
as sure as there is light.
I know...
that being was ancient.
Malevolent.
The desire to malign.
to pervert...
and consume.
given corporeal form.
If any of those things...
ever escape that well
down there...
...God help us all.
You want one for the camera?
No.
No. I'm good. Thank you.
Suit yourself.
Dr. M'Benga?
I have the subspace relay
to Earth.
Thank you.
I've got it from here.
Hello. I'm Dr. Joseph M'Benga
of the USS Enterprise.
I've asked to be the one
to call you.
It's about your son.
Dana Gamble.
Captioning sponsored by
CBS
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm